{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Boar","incorrectAnswers":["A Dog","A Tom","A Jack"],"question":"What is the word for a male badger?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Chloroplasts","incorrectAnswers":["Mitochondria","Vacuoles","Centrioles"],"question":"In which part of a plant does photosynthesis take place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"A Lagoon ","incorrectAnswers":["A Lake","An Atoll","An Archipelago"],"question":"What is a piece of shallow saltwater seperated from the deeper sea by coral or sand called?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"5 And 1","incorrectAnswers":["1 and 19","7 and 13","15 and 5"],"question":"What Numbers Are Either Side Of 20 On A Dartboard","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"It is used in laundry detergent.","incorrectAnswers":["It is used in nuclear reactors, as a neutron moderator.","It is used in used in military shells, bombs, and grenades.","It is used as oscillators in radios, watches."],"question":"What is the chemical sodium tetraborate decahydrate often used for?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Prince","incorrectAnswers":["Celine Dion","Barry Gibb","Elvis Presley"],"question":"Who Wrote The Songs \"Manic Monday\" , \"Nothing Compares To You\" And \"I Feel For You\"? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Murphy's law","incorrectAnswers":["Mendel's law","Newton's law","Boyle's law"],"question":"What term represents the belief that if something can go wrong, it will?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Vampires","incorrectAnswers":["Ghosts","Witches","Werewolves"],"question":"What has no reflection, no shadow, and can't stand the smell of garlic","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Ulotrichous","incorrectAnswers":["Conjubilant","Kakorrhaphiophobia","Sprunt"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'having wooly or crispy hair'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Molasses","incorrectAnswers":["Pursy","Nectar","Crystallis"],"question":"What is the name of the syrup drained from raw sugar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Wonderwall\" by Oasis","incorrectAnswers":["\"SpongeBob SquarePants Theme\" by Painty the Pirate","\"I'll Make a Man Out of You\" by Donny Osmond","\"Baby Got Back\" by Sir Mix-a-Lot"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"And Today is gonna be the day that they're gonna throw it back to you.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bodega","incorrectAnswers":["Bologna","Bogota","Boloney"],"question":"In New York, what is a corner store called?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Oliver Cromwell","incorrectAnswers":["Martin Luther","Francis Bacon","Gregor Mendel"],"question":"Which influential historical person was leader of \nthe  Parliamentarians in the English civil war?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'Only Girl (In the World)'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1960","incorrectAnswers":["1941","1980","1971"],"question":"In which year did Sirimavo Bandaranaike make history as the first woman elected head of a government?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"We Three Kings","incorrectAnswers":["I Saw Three Ships","Once In Royal David's City","Good King Wenceslas"],"question":"The words \"Myrrh is mine, its bitter perfume breathes of life, of gathering gloom___\" come from which Christmas carol?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Saints","incorrectAnswers":["Gators","Rockets","Brass"],"question":"American Football: The New Orleans __________.","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Niccolo Machiavelli","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Ludwig Wittgenstein","Karl Marx"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'God is not willing to do everything, and thus take away our free will and that share of glory which belongs to us'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Top Gun","incorrectAnswers":["Lost in Translation","Snakes on a Plane","Sully"],"question":"Which Hollywood film was retitled to \"Love in the Sky\" in Israel?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Percy Bysshe Shelley","incorrectAnswers":["H. Rider Haggard","Charles Darwin","Agatha Christie"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Ozymandias'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austin","incorrectAnswers":["Boston","Dallas","Houston"],"question":"What is the capital of Texas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Berlin","incorrectAnswers":["Munich","Hamburg","Frankfurt"],"question":"What is the capital city of Germany?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"One Thousand and One Nights","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte's Web","Alice's Adventures in Wonderland","The Snow Queen"],"question":"In which book does 'Harun al-Rashid' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fyodor Dostoyevsky","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Leo Tolstoy","Mikhail Bulgakov"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Idiot'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Chronicles of Narnia","incorrectAnswers":["His Dark Materials","Twilight","Ender's Game"],"question":"In which book series would you find 'Peter Pevensie'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Abel Tasman","incorrectAnswers":["James Cook","Christopher Columbus","John Cabot"],"question":"Who was the first European to sight New Zealand in 1642?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Green","Yellow","Gold"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Cambodia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"R.E.M.","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American alternative rock band released the studio album 'New Adventures in Hi-Fi'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dravidian","incorrectAnswers":["Afroasiatic","Japonic","Koreanic"],"question":"The language 'Kannada' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Succotash","incorrectAnswers":["Rösti","Plov","Pad Thai"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Equatorial Guinea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cactus","incorrectAnswers":["Orchid","Palm","Sugar Cane"],"question":"From which plant is tequila derived?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Whale shark","incorrectAnswers":["Great White shark","Hammerhead shark","Tiger shark"],"question":"What is the name of the largest species of sharks, which can reach lengths of up to 40 feet?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"C. S. Lewis","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","Jack Vance","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Silver Chair'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["France","Italy","Austria"],"question":"Where were the 1920 Olympics held?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"2","incorrectAnswers":["0","4","10"],"question":"What Is The Only Even Prime Number? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Venta Bulgarum","incorrectAnswers":["Aquae Sulis","Londinium","Camulodunum"],"question":"As what was Winchester known by the Romans?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ayo","incorrectAnswers":["Agent Peggy Carter","Agent Maria Hill","Jane Foster"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Florence Kasumba?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Kinetic","incorrectAnswers":["Potential","Thermal","Static"],"question":"What adjective, from the Greek word for 'moving', describes the mechanical energy of an object due to motion?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"An egg laying mammal","incorrectAnswers":["A single sailed boat","A form of colour blindness","A stringed instrument"],"question":"What is a monotreme?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Turkey","Spain","Estonia"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Sushi?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Accra","incorrectAnswers":["Port-au-Prince","Chisinau","Ashgabat"],"question":"What is the capital city of Ghana?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Supremes","incorrectAnswers":["The Attractions","The Vandellas","The Four Tops"],"question":"Which band was Diana Ross a member of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Apricots","incorrectAnswers":["Coins","The offspring of Hera and Zeus","The stars in the night sky"],"question":"What were the 'Golden Apples' in Greek myth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Amazon","incorrectAnswers":["Congo","Yangtze","Mississippi"],"question":"While cruising down what river in 1542 was Francisco de Orellana attacked by female warriors that gave it its name?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"George Clooney","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Connery","Gary Oldman","Ewan McGregor"],"question":"Which actor has had roles in films including Tomorrowland and Gravity?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ghana","incorrectAnswers":["Latvia","Uzbekistan","Portugal"],"question":"Accra is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Star Fruit ","incorrectAnswers":["Durian","Guava","Dragon Fruit"],"question":"What is another name for the carambola?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beach Boys","incorrectAnswers":["Swans","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which band includes 'Dennis Wilson'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Diamonds","incorrectAnswers":["Gold","Coal","Iron"],"question":"What did the De Beers Mining Company, established in 1880, mine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Alice Springs ","incorrectAnswers":["Perth","Canberra","Darwin"],"question":"Which Town Is Situated Closest To The Geographic Centre Of Australia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"9 Ladies Dancing","incorrectAnswers":["9 Lords a Leaping","9 Calling Birds","9 Pipers Piping"],"question":"What did 'my true love give to me' on the ninth day of Christmas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Philip Pullman","incorrectAnswers":["J. R. R. Tolkien","Christopher Tolkien","Neil Gaiman"],"question":"Which author wrote 'His Dark Materials trilogy'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Dire Straits","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","The Moody Blues","The Shadows"],"question":"Which British rock band released the studio album 'Brothers in Arms'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Loki","incorrectAnswers":["Iron Man","Black Panther","Spiderman"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Tom Hiddleston?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Tim Curry","incorrectAnswers":["Aaron Paul","Mark Hamill","Richard Burton"],"question":"Which actor has played roles in films including The Rocky Horror Picture Show and The Hunt for Red October?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The dead sea scrolls","incorrectAnswers":["The shroud of Turin","The grotto of the nativity","The Azekah inscription"],"question":"What did a shepherd boy discover at Qumram, Israel in 1947?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Atlantic City","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago","Las Vegas","Miami"],"question":"Which city setting was the focus of the TV show \"Boardwalk Empire\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Australia","incorrectAnswers":["Canada","The Republic of Ireland","United States"],"question":"In which country is the Samuel Griffith Society headquartered, dedicated to upholding the constitution of said nation?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pastis","incorrectAnswers":["Whisky","Mastika","Caesar"],"question":"Which of these drinks originates from France?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Menudo","incorrectAnswers":["Gazpacho","Pho","Gumbo"],"question":"Which of these is a Mexican tripe soup?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Comoros","incorrectAnswers":["Nepal","Hungary","Liberia"],"question":"Moroni is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Badminton","Swimming","Cycling"],"question":"With which sport is Roger Federer associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"4","incorrectAnswers":["3","5","1"],"question":"Which of these numbers is not a factor of 15?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Pakistan","incorrectAnswers":["Kosovo","Saudi Arabia","Ghana"],"question":"Islamabad is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Anesthesia","incorrectAnswers":["Amnesia","Hypnosis","Paralysis"],"question":"Which of these medical terms comes from an Ancient Greek word meaning \"without sensation\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Pepper\" by Butthole Surfers","incorrectAnswers":["\"Yo Home to Bel-Air\"","\"What I Got\" by Sublime","\"Let's Go Crazy\" by Prince and The Revolution"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Marky got with Sharon / Sharon got Sherice / She was sharing Sharon's outlook / On the topic of disease / Mikey had a facial scar / And Bobby was a racist / They were all in love with dyin' / They were doing it in Texas...\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dallas","incorrectAnswers":["Atlanta","Austin","Houston"],"question":"In Which City Was John F Kennedy Assassinated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the studio album 'Talk That Talk'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Slumdog Millionaire","incorrectAnswers":["The Curious Case of Benjamin Button","Frost/Nixon","Milk"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2008?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Wiener Schnitzel","incorrectAnswers":["Plov","Döner Kebab","Pho"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most associated with Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Brawn ","incorrectAnswers":["Trotters","Skippets","Swain"],"question":"What is the name of the traditional English dish made from pork trimmings and pig's head?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Roxette","incorrectAnswers":["Arch Enemy","Sabaton","Europe"],"question":"Whose Greatest Hits Album Was Entitled \"Don't Bore Us With The Chorus\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dwight D. Eisenhower","incorrectAnswers":["Bernard Montgomery","Erwin Rommel","Arthur Tedder"],"question":"Who was appointed Supreme Allied Commander during the invasion of the Normandy in 1944?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Through the Looking-Glass","incorrectAnswers":["Mio, My Son","Jonathan Strange & Mr Norrell","The Stand"],"question":"In which book does 'The Hatter' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dmitri Mendeleev","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Faraday","James Clerk Maxwell","Marie Curie"],"question":"Who devised the periodic table of elements?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Romeo","incorrectAnswers":["Juliet","Macbeth","Mercutio"],"question":"Who's last words were \"Thus with a kiss I die\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Germany","incorrectAnswers":["France","Spain","Italy"],"question":"During World War 2, which country was home to the White Rose, a group of student rebels fighting against fascism?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Green Book","incorrectAnswers":["Black Panther","BlacKkKlansman","Bohemian Rhapsody"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2018?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hibiscus","incorrectAnswers":["Orchid","Lavender","Rose"],"question":"Which plant is known for attracting hummingbirds?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Diego Rivera","incorrectAnswers":["‎Salvador Dalí","Paul Cézanne","Vincent van Gogh"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Flower Carrier\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neil Gaiman","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","H. P. Lovecraft","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Coraline'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Metamorphosis","incorrectAnswers":["The Sound and the Fury","The Quiet American","Parade's End"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Gregor Samsa'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"David Bowie","incorrectAnswers":["The Beatles","The Rolling Stones","Elton John"],"question":"Who Released The Album 'Hunky Dory'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A prince cursed to spend his days as a monster sets out to regain his humanity.","incorrectAnswers":["A paleontologist is tasked with protecting two children when cloned dinosaurs are set free.","The son of a former boxer is trained by his father for a mixed martial arts tournament.","A young F.B.I. cadet must receive the help of a cannibal to help catch another serial killer."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Beauty and the Beast?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queensrÿche","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American band performed the concept album 'Operation: Mindcrime'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Thirty Years' War","incorrectAnswers":["The Hundred Years' War","The War of the Roses","The War of Spanish Succession"],"question":"What was the name of the prominent religious conflict that arose in Europe in the 17th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Lord of the Rings","incorrectAnswers":["The Searchers","Ghost","My Favorite Year"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Gollum'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Caustic soda","incorrectAnswers":["Quartz","Heavy water","Dolomite"],"question":"What is the common name for sodium hydroxide?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Kiss","incorrectAnswers":["The Embrace","The Burghers of Calais","The Separation"],"question":"What is the name of the sculpture by Rodin that portrays Paolo and Francesca, lovers from the Middle Ages?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Romanticism","incorrectAnswers":["Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","Post Impressionism","Primitivism"],"question":"The painting \"The Liberty leading the people\" by Eugène Delacroix is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Charlotte Hornets","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte Inter","Charlotte Magic","Charlotte Astros"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Charlotte?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Calypso","incorrectAnswers":["Discovery","Terra Nova","Beagle"],"question":"What was the name of Jacques Cousteau's research ship?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Charles Darwin","incorrectAnswers":["Percy Bysshe Shelley","H. Rider Haggard","Robert Louis Stevenson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Origin of Species'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Johannes Kepler","incorrectAnswers":["Mahavira","Francisco Pizarro","Galileo Galilei"],"question":"Which influential mathematician and astronomer created the laws of planetary motion?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Francisco Quevedo","incorrectAnswers":["Miguel de Cervantes","Oscar Wilde","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Spanish Parnassus'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Reece's Pieces","incorrectAnswers":["M&M's","Smores","Twinkies"],"question":"What was E.T.'s favorite candy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Waterford","incorrectAnswers":["Swarovaski","Dublin","Cork"],"question":"Which Irish city is famous for its crystal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Mexico ","incorrectAnswers":["France","China","India"],"question":"Which country is the ancient home of chocolate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Human history through excavation","incorrectAnswers":["The characteristics of the skull","Sex","The cultivation of fruits"],"question":"What is Archaeology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},